<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on HOME</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on HOME</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Drawing chromHMM legend with ggplot2</title>
      <link>/blog/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/test/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post, I use ggplot() to plot a legend for chromHMM annotation.
chromHMM uses a Hidden Markov Model to integrate a range of epigenetic markers and predicts the chromatin states, like Transcription Start Sites or enhancers.
The table I use here comes from website: ROADMAP epigenetics project web portal. I copied the table from the website and saved it in a file called “coreChromHMM.txt”. The headers of the table are “STATE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysing sleeping data from Mi 3 band</title>
      <link>/blog/sleepdata/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/sleepdata/</guid>
      <description>With the advent of wearable devices, we now have the ability to collect a wide range of personal health and lifestyle data, giving us the opportunity to take a closer look like what our lifestype look like.
Mi 3 Fit band, for instance, collects users&amp;rsquo; sleep data by recording how actively they are moving, and uses this information to decide whether the user is in light or deep sleep or somber.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drawing chromHMM legend with ggplot2</title>
      <link>/blog/chromhmmlegend/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/chromhmmlegend/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post, I use ggplot() to plot a legend for chromHMM annotation.
chromHMM uses a Hidden Markov Model to integrate a range of epigenetic markers and predicts the chromatin states, like Transcription Start Sites or enhancers.
The table I use here comes from website: ROADMAP epigenetics project web portal. I copied the table from the website and saved it in a file called &amp;ldquo;coreChromHMM.txt&amp;rdquo;. The headers of the table are &amp;ldquo;STATE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phyllotaxis with R</title>
      <link>/blog/phyllotaxis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/phyllotaxis/</guid>
      <description>Phycllotaxis is a kind of &amp;lsquo;seemingly&amp;rsquo; complex geometric pattern that looks complex but with very simple mathematics behind. It is not uncommon in nature. According to Wikipedia, phycllotaxis &amp;ldquo;is the arrangement of leaves on a plant stem&amp;rdquo; in botany. The following code show how to draw phycllotaxis patterns using ggplot2. The code was modified from a Project called PHYLLOTAXIS: DRAW FLOWERS USING MATHEMATICS on Datacamp.
library(tidyverse) library(ggplot2) angle &amp;lt;- 31*pi/180 points &amp;lt;- 900 t &amp;lt;- (1:points)*angle x &amp;lt;- sin(t) y &amp;lt;- cos(t) df &amp;lt;- data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>boringR: drawing with R</title>
      <link>/blog/boringr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/boringr/</guid>
      <description>R provides us with a graphical tool that is precise, beautiful and easy to learn. Besides academic publishing, R can also be used to do arts. Inspired by some blogs, I also tried to creat something beautiful and interesting by R. I call this &amp;ldquo;boringR&amp;rdquo; and you can find all the code on my Github repo.
Here I would to share with you some of my codes and my creations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>